Guide to the Rice University Presidential Inaugural Committee Records: President Norman Hackerman, 1971 UA 117
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Presidential Inaugural Committee Records: President Norman Hackerman
1971
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 117
5 Linear Feet (8 boxes)
Correspondence, memos, schedules, etc. generated by the Presidential Inaugural Committee planning the Inauguration of Norman Hackerman as the fourth president of Rice University on September 24, 1971.
Biographical / Historical
The Presidential Inaugural Committee is charged with the overall planning of the presidential inauguration and the events surrounding it.
Eighty years after the incorporation of Rice Institute in 1891 came the inauguration of the university's fourth president, Norman Hackerman, former president of the University of Texas at Austin and professor of chemistry.
On Sept. 23, 1971, H. Malcolm Lovett, chairman of the Board of Governors, knocked on the President's House door and presented Dr. Hackerman with the formal summons to appear for his inauguration the following day, starting with a new Rice inauguration tradition based on a ritual used by British universities.
Delegates and special guests representing 175 institutions of higher learning and 50 learned and professional societies attended the ceremonies.
Dr. Logan Wilson, president of the American Council on Education and former Chancellor of the University of Texas, gave an address on "Rice University's Widening Horizons." Professor Harold Rorschach presided at the inaugural dinner, which featured three speakers, representing the arts, science, and letters. Writer / pilot MacKinlay Kantor spoke on "Letters". Geneticist George W. Beadle spoke on "Science and the University". Jack Joseph Valenti, president of the Motion Picture Association of America, spoke on "Art".
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, memos, schedules, etc. generated by the Presidential Inaugural Committee planning the Inauguration of Norman Hackerman as the fourth president of Rice University on September 24, 1971.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Presidential Inaugural Committee.
Related Material
See also Norman Hackerman presidential papers at WRC.
Index Terms
Subjects
College teachers; Universities and colleges
Subjects (Persons)
Hackerman, Norman
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University; Rice University. Office of the President
- Series I: Volume 1, 92659
  - Preliminary Memos, Notes, Etc., 92677 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Inaugural Committee, 92676 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Committee Meetings, 92675 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Schedule of Inaugural Events, 92674 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Invitations-Class II/Guest List & Responses, 92673 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence re: invitations, 92672 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Invitations-Institutions of Higher Learning- Class I, 92671 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Invitations-Learned Societies-Class I, 92670 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Delegates-Institutions of Higher Learning, 92669 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Delegates-Learned Societies (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence with delegates, 92668 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Delegates' packets, 92667 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Publicity and PR-Hotel Information, 92666 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Medallion & Art Inst. Display, 92665 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Transportation, 92664 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Memos and Forms Sent to Faculty, 92663 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Precedence Lists, 92662 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Marshals, 92661 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Scenario, 92660 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Series II: Volume 2, 92651
  - Invitation Order & Samples of Order, 92658 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Program Orders, 92657 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Summons, 92656 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Samples from Pitzer's Inauguration, 92655 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Budget, 92654 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bills & Invoices, 92653 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bills mischarged, 92652 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Sewall Hall Dedication: Bills and Invoices (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Series III: Volume 3, 92636
  - Physical Facilities, etc., 92650 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Music, 92649 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Talks and remarks made at Inaugural Ceremony, 92648 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Inaugural Program, 92647 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Official Party (For Platform), 92646 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cocktail Party given by Inaugural Committee, 92645 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Inaugural Dinner, 92644 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Parking, 92643 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Prospective Speakers, 92642 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Speakers, 92641 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Proceedings, 92640 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Dedication of Sewall Hall Ceremonies, 92639 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Campus Publications re: Inauguration, 92638 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Thank you letters from Inaugural Chairman, 92637 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Series IV: Invitations and Responses
  - Cocktail-Buffet-Guest Responses, 1970-09-16 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cocktail-Buffet-Invitations, Guest Lists, Correspondences, 1970-09-16 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Cocktail Party-Invitation and Guest List, 1971-09-24 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - College Presidents-Arrangements (For Other) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Delegates at Inauguration (Corrected Copy) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Delegates/Institutions-Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Delegates-Instruction Packets (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Delegates-Luncheon Lists for Colleges (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Hotel Reservations (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Inaugural Committee (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Inaugural Dinner-Seating Arrangements (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Inaugural-Planning Research (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Inaugural Summons (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Institute of the Arts Exhibit, 1971-09-23 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Inaugural Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Sewall Hall Dedication Ceremonies, 1971-09-25 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Inaugural Invitations Engraver's Plates (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Inaugural Invitations-Estimated Costs (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Inaugural Invitations-Ordered (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Inaugural Invitations-Proofs For Overprinting of #1 Invitation (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Inaugural Invitations-RSVP For #1 and #2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Inaugural Invitations-Worksheets for #1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Inaugural Invitations-Worksheets For #2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Inaugural invitations-Worksheets for #3 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Invitations/Programs-Communication Competition, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Invitations/Programs-Sample Packets (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Invitations/Programs-Transfer List (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Invitations/Programs-Extra Copies/Dinner and Coffee Invitation (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Invitations/Programs-Extra Copies/Inaugural Dinner (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Invitations/Programs-Extra Copies/Inaugural Invitations (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Invitations/Programs-Extra Copies/Inaugural Program (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Invitations/Programs-Extra Copies/Information for Delegates (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Invitations/Programs-Extra Copies/Information For Guests (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Invitations/Programs-Extra Copies/Sewall Hall Dedication (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Series V: Congratulations and Testimonials
  - Indiana University Congratulations to Norman Hackerman, 1971-09-24 (Box 6, Item 1)
  - Knox College Congratulations to Norman Hackerman, 1971-09-24 (Box 6, Item 2)
  - Ohio University Congratulations to Norman Hackerman, 1971-09-24 (Box 6, Item 3)
  - University of Minnesota Congratulations to Norman Hackerman, 1971-09-24 (Box 6, Item 4)
  - University of Mississippi Congratulations to Norman Hackerman, 1971-09-24 (Box 6, Item 5)
  - Letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Telegrams (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Testimonials-A-G (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Testimonials-H-T (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Testimonials-U-University M (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - University N-Y (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - University of Notre Dame Congratulations to Norman Hackerman, 1971-09-24 (Box 7, Item 1)
  - University of Oklahoma Congratulations to Norman Hackerman, 1971-09-21 (Box 7, Item 2)
  - Vanderbilt University Congratulations to Norman Hackerman, 1971-09-24 (Box 7, Item 3)
- Series VI: Inauguration Scrapbook
  - Inauguration Photo Scrapbook, 1971-09-24 (Box 8, Item 1)
  - Inauguration Photo Scrapbook, 1971-09-24 (Box 8, Item 2)